# Nash Reddy

Brisbane City, Queensland, Australia



nash.surapureddy@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/nashreddy4

## Summary

An experienced professional with a solid background in devising IT solutions for improved business efficiency. Highly focused on end user satisfaction through quality delivery of services. I thrive working in a fast pace environment that requires problem solving, implementing new ideas and delivering enhanced customer experience.

## **Experience**



### Application Analyst

**Bolton Clarke** 

Dec 2018 - Present (3 years 10 months +)

Perform analysis of existing application protocols and software tools.

Hands on experience on Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, CI/CD, Terraform, Prometheus and Grafana Dashboards.

Developed automation processes using Python to reduce extensive manual processing to a short automated process.

Design and develop a new application architecture that supports business growth.

Provide and support recommendations for improved procedures and policies.

Provide application support in resolving and troubleshooting problems.

Assist and support in achieving departmental goals and objectives.

Provide advanced application support to utilise the system infrastructure and resources effectively.

Provide direct assistance to users in using and interpreting software tools and products.

Interact with software vendors to provide the best solutions to business problems.

Provide application support to other internal users and developers in handling multiple projects.

Ensure compliance with all security measures in application development processes.

Plan and implement application releases. In addition, I work with vendors and business stakeholders to evaluate new releases and guide the testing approach.

Ensure non-prod environments are configured and maintained systematically to conserve the integrity of the testing processes.

Provide data extraction and high-quality analysis on an ad-hoc basis to help inform critical business decisions and metrics.

Propose, Plan and Deliver changes efficiently by following ITIL methodologies, outlining potential risks and impacts on the user



### **Software Developer**

**MVP Studio** 

Jun 2018 - Nov 2018 (6 months)

MVP Studio is an incubator for software start-ups.

I worked on a Keys project, an Automated, Intelligent property investment platform.

Worked on C#, ASP.NET MVC, JIRA, HTML/JavaScript/React/CSS/ jQuery, SQL2012 Involved in Daily Stand-up meetings,

Involved in Keys project feasibility study and provided technical solutions.

I created a page that appears when a Tenant signs up for the first time. It has a form that gets the tenant's personal information.

Involved in project Sprints and completed assigned tasks.

Having experience in SDLC and Agile work environments

### AIR

### IT Production Controller

#### AIA

Jan 2016 - Apr 2018 (2 years 4 months)

- Experienced in the implementation of small, medium and large projects on .Net & SQL Technologies
- · Experienced in installing, maintaining and monitoring Windows servers and applications on-premises
- performed server hardening and house-keeping
- Performed SQL database administration such as backup, restoration and truncation
- Administered backup tapes and rotated as required
- Expertise in operational support and maintenance of business-critical in-house applications with a high focus on quality and efficiency improvement
- Had experience in SDLC and Agile work environments
- Involved in feasible project study and provided technical solutions. Completed several end-to-end projects
- Maintain high system availability and distribute the reports to users promptly
- Perform file backup and restore operation following client requirements, mapping network shared drives and maintaining AD security groups.
- Prepare and implement system and security patches.
- Promote the software releases to a Production environment
- Administration of the AS400 Environment, including capacity, job scheduling and availability
- Coordinate with Application services and vendors in resolving technical/application problems and changes in the operating environment
- · System monitoring and house-keeping
- · On call for nightly cycle runs
- Carry out job recovery & special processing requests such as SPRR, PTRR, Restoration, Backup
- Maintain accurate document and record control
- Maintain Technical and compliance IT documentation as required, Giving IT induction training to new starters and basic training on Microsoft products.

## 

### AIA

Jan 2014 - Jan 2016 (2 years 1 month)

- Good Knowledge of ITIL Service Management Practices
- Good experience in resolving BAU tickets by following SLA. Supported end-user tickets face-to-face, by phone and by using remote application tools.
- Troubleshooting and Identifying the issues involved with administering and maintaining corporate infrastructure, including network connectivity and Internet access.
- Identifying the issues involved in administering and maintaining corporate WAN
- Troubleshooting & software support for PCs running Windows XP and Windows 7, Office 365, handheld devices and Enterprise activation
- Troubleshooting and maintenance of servers
- · Hands-on installation of hardware, software upgrades and configuring systems and applications
- User group management & user server migration

- · Internal IT audit
- Upkeep of Application suite for email, messaging, Instant Messaging and Mobile devices
- · Digital Data management
- Involved in McAfee EEPC 7.0 SS0 security Software upgrade project.
- Administration experience on Checkpoint, McAfee e-policy Orchestrator, NSM, Bluecoat, Print Server and Backup Server.
- Experience in product Procurement.

## IT Systems Analyst

### Vodafone

Mar 2012 - Jan 2014 (1 year 11 months)

- · Managed and maintained relationships with SME customers as a single contact
- Provided technical support to customers through phone, email and tickets
- Analysed and troubleshot software and hardware issues
- Helped customers identify and resolve technical problems
- · Created help desk documentation with instructions for problem-solving techniques

### **Education**



Diploma In Computing- Level 7, System, Networking, and LAN/WAN Management/ Manager

2013 - 2014

## i Sri Krishnadevaraya University

Master of Electronics, Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2002 - 2004

### **Licenses & Certifications**

CCNA ROUTING & SWITCHING - Cisco

Issued Nov 2013 - Expires Nov 2016 CSCO12429037

CCNA Security - Cisco

Issued Nov 2013 - Expires Nov 2016 CSCO12429037

MCTS SQL 2008 Implementation and Maintenance - Microsoft E421-7694

### **Skills**

Terraform • Microsoft SQL Server • Internet Information Services (IIS) • Python (Programming Language) HTML5
Package Management
BUILD MANAGER
Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Jenkins • DOCKER

### **Honors & Awards**



### Best Employee Award - AIA

Jul 2014

Got the best employee award for the month of May & June



## Information Systems Security (INFOSEC) Professional - Cisco Systems, Inc.

Nov 2013

This recognition indicates confidence in the competency of my skills.

The NSTISSI (National Security

Telecommunications and Information Systems Security)

No. 4011 National Training Standard for Information

Systems Security (INFOSEC)

Professionals applies to all U.S. Government departments and agencies, as well

as

to its contractors. Therefore, this recognition will help me to meet current or

future Federal employment

requirements. In environments where these requirements

do not apply, I can use this recognition to

demonstrate that I possess the

knowledge and skills needed to oversee and protect critical information

infrastructures and networks



### Best Customer Service Award / Smile Award - AIA

Apr 2015